Zoe: Circumstances in which it
can sometimes be important to
disclose confidential information
is when there's a safety issue.
So when sharing information is in
the best interest of the safety
of the child or young person.
Even then, it's important to explain
to the child, or young person that
you plan to share that information.
Ellen: When it comes to
safeguarding concerns, we have
to protect that young person.
Say if they came to us with really
serious information, like they might say
"such and such has happened at home".
You know, they might say to us, "oh
please, can you not tell anyone?"
But we can't promise that we have
to say, "look, we don't want to,
but, to protect you we might have
to tell our safeguarding lead".
Phil: It was discovered that there was
a safeguarding issue then obviously
that would need to be shared with the
designated safeguarding lead and the
appropriate step following a safeguarding
policy, basically, but that's if there
was a need and which is why, again, you
can't promise a young person that you'll
keep something confidential because there
may be a safeguarding issue, somebody
may be at risk themselves or others,
and that information would need to be
passed up for safeguarding reasons.
Zoe T: Really it's just, if it's a
safeguard in issue, if it's going to
cause harm to that person or they're
going to cause harm to somebody else.
I mean, there isn't really
any justification for
breaching confidentiality
under any other circumstances.
Phil: Information to be shared with
other staff only if there was a
risk  and it needed to be shared.
And again, that would probably
be staff higher up that that
need to know not all staff would
need to be aware of every detail.
Kerry: And then it's things
like on a need to know basis.
It shouldn't just be, for example,
chatted about in the staff room.
Say medication as an example, not
everybody that works here needs
to know what medication child A
is on, but the people who work
with him and those that give that
medication halfway through the day.